<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Linux processes on</title><link>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/linux/processes/</link><description>Recent content in Linux processes on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:49:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/linux/processes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction to Linux processes</title><link>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/linux/processes/introduction/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/linux/processes/introduction/</guid><description>What is a process? # When you execute a Linux command, the Bash session creates a process.
A process is a running instance of a program.
Every process has a process identifier (often abbreviated pid).
During execution, a process changes between states depending on its environment and circumstances. The most common states are:
Running &amp;ndash; The process is actively running on the system. Waiting &amp;ndash; The process is waiting for an event to occur or for a system resource.</description></item><item><title>Monitor processes</title><link>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/linux/processes/monitor-processes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/linux/processes/monitor-processes/</guid><description>Snapshot current processes # The ps command can be used to report a snapshot of the current processes.
ps The output of the ps command will always include at least two entries:
The bash process that is used to run the current Bash session. The ps process itself, which is being being executed to snapshot currently running processes. Then, any other process that is currently running will be reported by the ps command.</description></item><item><title>Resilience to loss of connection</title><link>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/linux/processes/hangup/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/linux/processes/hangup/</guid><description>What happens when the connection is lost? # The connection to a Bash session on the CCB cluster may be lost for a number of reasons:
Loss of internet connection anywhere between your computer and the CCB cluster. Power loss causing an unexpected outage of CCB systems. Loss of connection to the University VPN (if applicable). When the connection to a Bash session is lost, the HUP (hangup) signal is sent to the Bash session.</description></item></channel></rss>