<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Configuration on</title><link>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/linux/configuration/</link><description>Recent content in Configuration on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:49:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/linux/configuration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The .bashrc file</title><link>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/linux/configuration/bashrc/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/linux/configuration/bashrc/</guid><description>Motivation # Every time you open a new shell on the CCB cluster, you are given a new session in a Bash environment in your Terminal application.
In those new sessions, you may find yourself repetitively typing the same set of commands to set up the environment of that session before you are able to work.
The file ~/.bashrc is a Shell script that Bash runs whenever it is started interactively.</description></item><item><title>Environment variables</title><link>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/linux/configuration/environment-variables/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/linux/configuration/environment-variables/</guid><description>Motivation # A variable is a named place in a computer&amp;rsquo;s memory that stores a particular piece of information (e.g., number, string).
Environment variables are variables defined and available in the shell&amp;rsquo;s environment. Those variables can be accessed by any program that runs in the shell. They can be accessed using the $ (dollar) symbol, followed by the name of the environment variable (e.g., $USER).
Once logged into the CCB cluster, a number of environment variables are set in the Bash session.</description></item><item><title>Advanced configuration</title><link>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/linux/configuration/advanced/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/linux/configuration/advanced/</guid><description>.bashrc # Alternative login shells # The ~/.bashrc file is a script that is only read by the Bash login shell. The CCB cluster using Bash, this login shell should be the only one that you edit and worry about.
You may come across mention of other login shells (e.g., ~/.profile, ~/.bash_profile).
Those other files perform a task similar to the ~/.bashrc file, albeit with subtle differences with respect to the order and the environment in which they are executed.</description></item></channel></rss>