<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Connect to CCB on</title><link>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/connect/</link><description>Recent content in Connect to CCB on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:49:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/connect/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/connect/introduction/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/connect/introduction/</guid><description>What this documentation is # This documentation describes the user-facing MRC WIMM CCB cluster infrastructure, how to connect to the CCB cluster, and best practices for using common software on the cluster.
This documentation focuses on introductory scenarios and simple use cases. For further reading, trusted sources of information are listed on the page Links to external resources.
Who this documentation is for # This documentation is written for members of staff entitled to hold a CCB account.</description></item><item><title>Apply for an account</title><link>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/connect/apply/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/connect/apply/</guid><description>Get started # Apply for an account on the CCB Account and Support → page.
👉 The MRC WIMM CCB services are available only to members of staff and eligible collaborators. Full account # A full account gives access to all of our base resources, including free admission to all CCB introductory bioinformatics training courses.
Weatherall Institute of Molecular Medicine (WIMM), Ludwig Institute of Cancer Research (LICR) and Department of Biochemistry pay a service charge to help fund the CCB and there are no additional charges.</description></item><item><title>VPN setup</title><link>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/connect/vpn-setup/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/connect/vpn-setup/</guid><description>Motivation # When your device is not directly connected to the University campus network (e.g., when you are working from home or travelling), the VPN Service allows you to access the University campus network, and thus the CCB cluster.
The web page Virtual private network (VPN) → provide the latest information about requirements and instructions to set up recommended VPN clients. Most of the sections below refer to instructions on that page.</description></item><item><title>First SSH connection</title><link>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/connect/ssh-first-connection/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/connect/ssh-first-connection/</guid><description>Login nodes # The CCB cluster has three login nodes that users can log into:
cbrglogin1.molbiol.ox.ac.uk cbrglogin2.molbiol.ox.ac.uk cbrglogin3.molbiol.ox.ac.uk Log in with your username and password # When your account is created on the CCB cluster, you will be sent an email including your unique username on the CCB cluster and a randomly generated password.
To log into a login node, open a Terminal on your personal computer and use the ssh command, combining your username, the @ symbol, and the name of the login node that you wish to log into.</description></item><item><title>Change your SSH password</title><link>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/connect/ssh-change-password/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/connect/ssh-change-password/</guid><description>Motivation # The initial randomly generated password that you received by email is at risk of being stolen and misused if your email account were ever hacked. Separately, the randomness of the password makes it very difficult to remember and type manually.
It is highly recommended to change that initial password on your first connection to the CCB cluster.
Instructions # First, log into the CCB cluster as demonstrated on the page First SSH connection.</description></item><item><title>Set up an SSH key pair</title><link>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/connect/ssh-key-pair/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/connect/ssh-key-pair/</guid><description>Motivation # An SSH key pair can be used as an additional layer of security to connect to your account on the CCB HPC cluster. Instead of typing your username and password, it is possible to log into your account on the CCB cluster using a pair of files; one file on your personal computer (the &amp;ldquo;private&amp;rdquo; key), one file on the CCB cluster (the &amp;ldquo;public&amp;rdquo; key). Together, those two files enable your personal computer and the cluster to identify themselves to each other.</description></item><item><title>Configure an SSH host</title><link>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/connect/ssh-host/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/connect/ssh-host/</guid><description>Motivation # When regularly connecting to one or more remote hosts, it can be tedious to type or even remember all the parameters in the ssh command. Moreover, some parameters are common for multiple or all remote hosts, while other parameters are specific to individual hosts.
In this section, we describe how to configure parameters that are specific to different hosts.
Recommended parameters shared across all remote hosts are described in the earlier page Set up an SSH key pair.</description></item></channel></rss>