<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Configure SSH on</title><link>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/connect/ssh-configuration/</link><description>Recent content in Configure SSH on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:49:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/connect/ssh-configuration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Benefits of configuring SSH</title><link>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/connect/ssh-configuration/introduction/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/connect/ssh-configuration/introduction/</guid><description>Motivation # In the section First connection over SSH, we describe how to connect to the CCB cluster, typing all the information necessary to establish the connection at the Terminal prompt.
When connecting to CCB cluster on a regular basis &amp;ndash; often multiple times a day &amp;ndash;, typing that information becomes a tedious process that is also subject to typographical errors forcing users to start over the connection process.
Instead, the SSH client can be configured to ease the process of connection to remote computers.</description></item><item><title>Set up an SSH key pair</title><link>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/connect/ssh-configuration/ssh-key-pair/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/connect/ssh-configuration/ssh-key-pair/</guid><description>Motivation # An SSH key pair can be used as an additional layer of security to connect to your account on the CCB HPC cluster. Instead of typing your username and password, it is possible to log into your account on the CCB cluster using a pair of files; one file on your personal computer (the &amp;ldquo;private&amp;rdquo; key), one file on the CCB cluster (the &amp;ldquo;public&amp;rdquo; key). Together, those two files enable your personal computer and the cluster to identify themselves to each other.</description></item><item><title>Configure an SSH host</title><link>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/connect/ssh-configuration/ssh-host/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/connect/ssh-configuration/ssh-host/</guid><description>Motivation # When regularly connecting to one or more remote hosts, it can be tedious to type or even remember all the parameters in the ssh command. Moreover, some parameters are common for multiple or all remote hosts, while other parameters are specific to individual hosts.
In this section, we describe how to configure parameters that are specific to different hosts.
Recommended parameters shared across all remote hosts are described in the earlier page Set up an SSH key pair.</description></item><item><title>Advanced client configuration</title><link>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/connect/ssh-configuration/client-advanced/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/connect/ssh-configuration/client-advanced/</guid><description>Motivation # SSH clients can be configured through the configuration file ~/.ssh/config.
An example of this is demonstrated in the earlier page Set up an SSH key pair.
Some configuration settings are specific to individual operating systems. In the sections below, we provide a series of examples for the purpose of illustration and documentation.
Importantly, all the configuration parameters presented in this page are all optional. They are presented here for the purpose of information and help.</description></item></channel></rss>