<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Conda on</title><link>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/conda/</link><description>Recent content in Conda on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/conda/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction to Conda</title><link>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/conda/introduction/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/conda/introduction/</guid><description>Why use Conda? # The CCB cluster provides many bioinformatics software packages through the Environment Modules system, managed by system administrators.
When software is not available through the module system, users may use the Conda package management system to install software packages themselves, and even organise distinct environments that may contain different version of those software package for different projects.
Additionally, when installing a package, Conda identifies and resolves package dependencies, installing the latest appropriate version of every dependency for the target package.</description></item><item><title>Install Miniconda</title><link>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/conda/installation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/conda/installation/</guid><description>Download the installer # In a new Terminal application, log into the CCB cluster.
Download the latest Miniconda installer for Linux using the following command.
wget https://repo.anaconda.com/miniconda/Miniconda3-latest-Linux-x86_64.sh For reference, the URL to the installer file in the command above was obtained from the Latest Miniconda installer links.
Run the installer # Use bash to execute the installer file as demonstrated below.
bash Miniconda3-latest-Linux-x86_64.sh -b -p ~/conda Note the use of options to control the behaviour of the installer:</description></item><item><title>First steps with Conda</title><link>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/conda/first-steps/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/conda/first-steps/</guid><description>Pre-requisite # Activate the base Conda environment, as demonstrated in the page Install Miniconda.
Help and information # The conda --help command can be used to list the main sub-commands of the conda executable, along with a brief description of their purpose.
conda --help The conda info command can be used to display information about your current installation.
conda info 👉 You should always include the output of the 'conda info' command with all your bug reports, as that information provides important context for your own situation.</description></item><item><title>Use Conda environments</title><link>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/conda/environments/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/conda/environments/</guid><description>Motivation # Different projects often require different versions of the same program, or even mutually incompatible versions of different programs.
Conda provides the possibility to create and manage distinct environments, each containing a set of software packages that is independent from all other Conda environments on the same computer.
Upon initial installation (see section Install Miniconda), the Conda installer automatically creates an environment called base. We recommend keeping the base environment as minimal as possible, and creating new Conda environments for testing and working as required by individual projects.</description></item><item><title>Conda cheatsheet</title><link>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/conda/cheatsheet/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/conda/cheatsheet/</guid><description>Search available packages # The search command can be used to search for available packages and package versions programmatically.
For instance:
mamba search pysam The following websites can also be used to manually search packages available in individual channels:
bioconda: https://anaconda.org/bioconda/repo/ conda-forge: https://conda-forge.org/feedstock-outputs/index.html Install a specific package version # To install a specific version of a package, add the = symbol, followed by the specific version number.</description></item></channel></rss>