<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Organisation and backup on</title><link>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/data-management/organise-and-backup/</link><description>Recent content in Organisation and backup on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:49:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/data-management/organise-and-backup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Philosophy</title><link>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/data-management/organise-and-backup/philosophy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/data-management/organise-and-backup/philosophy/</guid><description>Citation # &amp;ldquo;Someone unfamiliar with your project should be able to look at your computer files and understand in detail what you did and why.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ndash; A Quick Guide to Organizing Computational Biology Projects - William Stafford Noble (Article →)
Overview # In this section, we will discuss:
Best practices for data storage &amp;amp; organisation. Rules and conventions for naming files. Typical components of genomics data analysis projects.</description></item><item><title>Name files carefully</title><link>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/data-management/organise-and-backup/filenames/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/data-management/organise-and-backup/filenames/</guid><description>Case-sensitivity # In Linux, file names are case-sensitive.
In the example below, a series of distinct files stored in the same directory differ only by the case-sensitivity of their filenames.
Exclusively using lowercase characters generally makes thigs easier and less confusing to remember.
Unicity within directories # File names must be unique within each directory.
Bearing in mind the case-sensitivity of filenames described above, all filenames within a given directory must be distinct.</description></item><item><title>Back up your work</title><link>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/data-management/organise-and-backup/backup/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/data-management/organise-and-backup/backup/</guid><description>Backups and archives # What is a backup? # A backup is a copy of important data that is stored in an alternative location, so that it can be recovered the original data is deleted or becomes corrupted.
What is an archive? # An archive is a copy of a completed project that has been stored on a remote computer for long-term storage with limited access.
Computer systems used to archive data often have reduced cost for disk usage over long periods of time, but longer access time to retrieve data.</description></item><item><title>Compress large files</title><link>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/data-management/organise-and-backup/compress/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/data-management/organise-and-backup/compress/</guid><description>Why compress files? # Disk space is a resource that even the largest High Performance Computing (HPC) clusters can run out of.
It is every user&amp;rsquo;s responsibility to manage their data files and ensure that they do not use excessive disk space unnecessarily.
Many programs automatically produce output files in compressed formats, to minimise their footprint on the disk space. When that is not the case, users are encouraged to compress large files themselves.</description></item><item><title>Delete intermediate files</title><link>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/data-management/organise-and-backup/delete/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/data-management/organise-and-backup/delete/</guid><description>Which files can be deleted? # Many bioinformatics workflows involve multiple steps of processing on certain files (e.g., filtering, sorting, annotation).
Those steps generate and store multiple copies of those files at the various steps of processing.
In such cases, you should consider deleting all but the final copy of that file.
For instance:
# Run HISAT2 to map reads hisat2 -f \ -x $HISAT2_HOME/example/index/22_20-21M_snp \ -U $HISAT2_HOME/example/reads/reads_1.fa \ -S example1.</description></item><item><title>Use symbolic links</title><link>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/data-management/organise-and-backup/symbolic-links/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/data-management/organise-and-backup/symbolic-links/</guid><description>What are symbolic links? # We describe symbolic links in the section Link to files and directories.
Briefly, a symbolic link is a shortcuts to target file or directory.
The link itself is materialised as a very small file that only indicates the location of the target file.
As such:
The size of the target file does not impact in any way the size of the symbolic link. A symbolic link will always be smaller than the target data file, or a copy of that file (unless the target file is empty).</description></item><item><title>Monitor your disk space quota</title><link>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/data-management/organise-and-backup/quota/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/data-management/organise-and-backup/quota/</guid><description>What is disk space quota? # Briefly, disk space quota are limits on the amount of disk space that individual users can use on a shared computing system.
Once a user exceeds their allowed disk space quota &amp;ndash; possibly after a set grace period &amp;ndash; they will not be able to create or edit any file in the filesystem until they either:
Delete or compress files, to return within their allowed quota (where possible).</description></item></channel></rss>