<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Setup on</title><link>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/python/setup/</link><description>Recent content in Setup on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:49:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/python/setup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Using Python on the CCB cluster</title><link>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/python/setup/ccb/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:49:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/python/setup/ccb/</guid><description>Overview # As well as the standard Python versions that you would normally expect, the CCB team additionally preinstalled hundreds of additional packages available for all to use. These are available via the python-cbrg module.
Basic usage # If you just want to get up and running with set of commonly used bioinformatics packages curated by the CCB team, you can do so with a single command:
module load python-cbrg 👉 The Spyder IDE is included in the standard Python installations.</description></item><item><title>Setup Python on macOS</title><link>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/python/setup/macos/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:49:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/python/setup/macos/</guid><description>👉 This section does not involve the CCB cluster at all. Instead, it provides a guide for installing a working Python environment on the macOS operating system. Install Visual Studio Code (VSCode) # Download the installer file # In your web browser, navigate to https://code.visualstudio.com/download.
Click on the button &amp;lsquo;Mac&amp;rsquo;, making sure that it matches the version of your operating system.
You may be redirected to another web page.</description></item><item><title>Setup Python on Windows</title><link>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/python/setup/windows/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:49:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/python/setup/windows/</guid><description>👉 This section does not involve the CCB cluster at all. Instead, it provides a guide for installing a working Python environment on the Windows operating system. Motivation # Instructions on this page should be followed in order to produce the desired effects, namely:
Visual Studio Code (VSCode) must be installed before Git Bash, so that VSCode may be specified as the default editor for Git. Git Bash must be installed before Anaconda Navigator, so that Anaconda Navigator may detect Git Bash on the system path.</description></item></channel></rss>