<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Linux essentials on</title><link>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/linux/essentials/</link><description>Recent content in Linux essentials on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:49:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/linux/essentials/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction to Linux and Bash</title><link>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/linux/essentials/introduction/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/linux/essentials/introduction/</guid><description>What is Linux? # Linux is an operating system (OS), like Microsoft Windows (MS Windows) and macOS.
However, Linux is open source and free of cost.
Linux and macOS are different, but share a large number of commands as macOS is based on BSD (Berkeley Standard Distribution) which is similar to Linux but not Linux.
More technical differences include:
File names are case-sensitive in Linux (and macOS) while they are not in MS Windows.</description></item><item><title>Autocompletion</title><link>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/linux/essentials/autocompletion/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/linux/essentials/autocompletion/</guid><description>What is autocompletion? # Autocompletion refer to the action of pressing the tabulation key after typing the first few characters of a command name or filepath, allowing the Terminal application to predict the rest of the word.
If the prediction unambiguously identifies a single match, the remaining characters are automatically inserted to complete the word. The user can then continue typing the rest of the command or filepath.
If the prediction identifies multiple matches, no autocompletion will take place.</description></item><item><title>Keyboard shortcuts</title><link>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/linux/essentials/keyboard-shortcuts/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/linux/essentials/keyboard-shortcuts/</guid><description>Navigate the history of commands # The up and down arrow keys can be used to navigate the history of commands used earlier in a Terminal session (or in an earlier Terminal session altogether).
👉 The left and right arrow keys have an entirely unrelated functionality; they navigate one character left or right within the command currently being typed at the prompt. Jump to the start/end of a line # The Control and A keys can be pressed simultaneously to move the cursor instantly at the start of the current line.</description></item><item><title>Helpful commands</title><link>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/linux/essentials/commands/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/linux/essentials/commands/</guid><description>Overview # This page introduces commands that are completely safe and purely display information that may be used by users to get help or explore the environment of the CCB cluster
echo # The echo command can be used to print a message or the value of a variable.
For instance:
echo 'Hello, world!' man # The man &amp;lt;page&amp;gt; command can be used to print the reference manual page &amp;lt;page&amp;gt;.</description></item><item><title>Wildcards</title><link>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/linux/essentials/wildcards/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/linux/essentials/wildcards/</guid><description>What are wildcards? # Wildcards are special characters that match one or more characters in filenames.
Wildcard Meaning * Matches any sequence of characters. ? Matches any single character. [characters] Matches any single character in a set. [!characters] Matches any single character not in a set. [[:class:]] Matches any character in the specified class. Many commands accept groups of files and directories matched using wildcards.</description></item></channel></rss>