<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>First steps on</title><link>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/connect/first-steps/</link><description>Recent content in First steps on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:49:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/connect/first-steps/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/connect/first-steps/introduction/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/connect/first-steps/introduction/</guid><description>What this documentation is # This documentation describes the user-facing MRC WIMM CCB cluster infrastructure, how to connect to the CCB cluster, and best practices for using common software on the cluster.
This documentation focuses on introductory scenarios and simple use cases. For further reading, trusted sources of information are listed on the page Links to external resources.
Who this documentation is for # This documentation is written for members of staff entitled to hold a CCB account.</description></item><item><title>Apply for an account</title><link>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/connect/first-steps/apply/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/connect/first-steps/apply/</guid><description>Get started # Apply for an account on the CCB Account and Support → page.
👉 The MRC WIMM CCB services are available only to members of staff and eligible collaborators. Full account # A full account gives access to all of our base resources, including free admission to all CCB introductory bioinformatics training courses.
Weatherall Institute of Molecular Medicine (WIMM), Ludwig Institute of Cancer Research (LICR) and Department of Biochemistry pay a service charge to help fund the CCB and there are no additional charges.</description></item><item><title>VPN setup</title><link>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/connect/first-steps/vpn-setup/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/connect/first-steps/vpn-setup/</guid><description>Motivation # When your device is not directly connected to the University campus network (e.g., when you are working from home or travelling), the VPN Service allows you to access the University campus network, and thus the CCB cluster.
The web page Virtual private network (VPN) → provide the latest information about requirements and instructions to set up recommended VPN clients. Most of the sections below refer to instructions on that page.</description></item><item><title>Microsoft Windows setup</title><link>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/connect/first-steps/windows-setup/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/connect/first-steps/windows-setup/</guid><description>Install Git Bash for Windows # Motivation # Microsoft Windows does not have a built-in Terminal emulator (The MS Windows Command Prompt cmd.exe is a command-line interpreter that does not include many of the commands needed to connect to the CCB cluster).
The primary function of the Git Bash for Windows program is to provide a Bash emulation used to run Git from the command line. Conveniently, in its effort to offer that functionality, the Terminal emulator of Git Bash for Windows also includes all the commands that you will need to connect to the CCB cluster.</description></item><item><title>First connection over SSH</title><link>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/connect/first-steps/ssh-first-connection/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/connect/first-steps/ssh-first-connection/</guid><description>What is SSH? # SSH stands for Secure Shell.
This refers to an encrypted network protocol for establishing a secure connection to a remote server. The connection is materialised as a remote command line login to a Linux system.
At its simplest, the protocol uses a username and password to authenticate a user on the remote system.
It can be used to log into the CCB cluster.
Choose a login node # The CCB cluster has three login nodes that users can log into using SSH:</description></item><item><title>Change your SSH password</title><link>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/connect/first-steps/ssh-change-password/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/connect/first-steps/ssh-change-password/</guid><description>Motivation # The initial randomly generated password that you received by email is at risk of being stolen and misused if your email account were ever hacked. Separately, the randomness of the password makes it very difficult to remember and type manually.
It is highly recommended to change that initial password on your first connection to the CCB cluster.
Instructions # First, log into the CCB cluster as demonstrated on the page First SSH connection.</description></item></channel></rss>