<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Bash on</title><link>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/bash/</link><description>Recent content in Bash on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:49:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/bash/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The .bashrc file</title><link>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/bash/bashrc/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/bash/bashrc/</guid><description>Motivation # Every time you connect to the CCB cluster, you are given a new session in a Bash environment in your Terminal application.
In those new sessions, you may find yourself repetitively typing the same set of commands to set up the environment of that session before you are able to work.
The file ~/.bashrc is a Shell script that Bash runs whenever it is started interactively. As such, this file is often edited to include commands that users wish to execute every time they log in, without the need to explicitly type them every time.</description></item><item><title>Built-in Bash commands</title><link>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/bash/commands/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/bash/commands/</guid><description>Motivation # Once logged into the CCB cluster, commands typed in a Terminal application are run in a Bash environment.
Bash is the shell, or command language interpreter, for the GNU operating system. The Bash interpreter includes a number of built-in commands that allow users to navigate and manage directories and files on the CCB cluster.
In this page, we provide a cheatsheet of the most commonly used commands along with a brief description of their purpose and advice on best practices.</description></item><item><title>Bash environment variables</title><link>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/bash/environment-variables/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://obds-training.github.io/Help/docs/bash/environment-variables/</guid><description>Motivation # Once logged into the CCB cluster, a number of environment variables are set in the Bash session.
Some environment variables are identical for all users on the cluster, other are derived from the username, and users can also set environment variables themselves. Many programs require certain environment variables to be set for their good functioning.
In this page, we describe some of the built-in environment variables, with a brief description of their purpose and advice on best practices.</description></item></channel></rss>